Joey Chiao-Yin Hsiao

jcyhsiao@umich.edu • +1 (734) 730-0963 • http://joeyhsiao.info 4365 N. Quad, 105 S. State St., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and Social Computing. My current topic is focused on how location-based social applications, such as people-nearby applications, hybrid community applications, sharing economy applications, can support newcomers in adapting to a new environment.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan

Doctoral Candidate in Information

Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt

National Taiwan University

M.S. in Computer Science

Advisor: Dr. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Carnegie Mellon University (Silicon Valley Campus)

Visiting Scholar

Advisor: Dr. Ted Selker National Taiwan University

B.S. in Computer Science

Ann Arbor, MI, USA 09/2015 – present

Taipei, Taiwan

09/2010 - 06/2013

Moffett Field, CA, USA

07/2012 - 09/2012

Taipei, Taiwan 09/2006 – 06/2010

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

• Hsiao, J. C.-Y. and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). Technology to Support Immigrant Access to Social Capital and Adaptation to a New Country. *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction*, Vol. 2, CSCW, Article 70. (acceptance rate: 25.6%; Presenter).

Conference Proceeding Papers

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Moser, C., Schoenebeck, S., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). The Role of Demographics, Trust, Computer Self-efficacy, and Ease of Use in the Sharing Economy. In *Proc. of the 1st ACM SIGCAS Conference on Computing and Sustainable Societies (COMPASS '18)*, Article 37 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2017). People-Nearby Applications: How Newcomers Move Their Relationships Offline and Develop Social and Cultural Capital. In *Proc. of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '17)*, 26-40 (acceptance rate: 33%; Presenter).
- Rajan, R., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lahoti, D., and Selker, T. (2013). "Roger that!" The Value of Adding Social Feedback in Audio-mediated Communications. In Proc. of IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction 2013 (INTERACT '13), 471-488 (acceptance rate: 31%).
- Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao**, **J. C.-Y.**, Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., Hu, J.-C., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Personal Soundscape. In *Proc. of International Association of Societies of Design Research 2013 (IASDR '13*), 5150-5160.

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Dillahunt, T. R. (2017) Detecting Life Changes: Increasing Opportunities to Benefit from People-Nearby Applications. In Proc. of *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2017 (CHI EA '17)*, 1700 1707 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015) Let's Solve It Together: Introducing Crowd Workers to Friendsourcing for Improving Creative Design. Presented at *The Taiwan Computer-Human Interaction Workshop 2015 (Tai-CHI '15)* (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015). The Price of the Priceless: Understanding Estimated Costs of Work in Friendsourcing. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2015 (CHI EA '15)*, 1893-1898 (Presenter).

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations (Cont.)

- Tsai, W.-C., Lee, H.-C., **Hsiao**, **J. C.-Y.**, Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Framing Design of Reminiscence Aids with Transactive Memory Theory. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2013 (CHI EA '13*), 331-336.
- Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao**, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). In Search of Lost Sounds: Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Everyday Soundscape. Presented at *The ACM conference on Designing Interactive Systems 2012 (DIS '12)*.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Jih, W.-R., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). Recognizing Continuous Social Engagement Level in Dyadic Conversation by Using Turn-taking and Speech Emotion Patterns. Presented at AAAI '12 Activity Context Representation Workshop (ACR '12) (Presenter).

Unpublished Theses and Research Reports

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2018). Social Network Matters: Opportunities for Technologies to Support Immigrants' Jobseeking. Field Prelim, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2017). Can People-Nearby Applications Benefit Newly-Arrived Immigrants? An Exploratory Study. *Pre-candidacy research paper*, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan.
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2012). Assessing Engagement in Conversation by Hierarchically Decomposing Emotion and Interaction. *Master's Thesis*, Dept. of Computer Science and Information Engineering (CSIE), Natl. Taiwan Univ.

HONOR

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

2019

Graduation Representative

Was chosen as the recognized master's student for leadership and active participation in student affairs of the department

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Social Innovations Group, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Research Assistant

09/2015 - present

Supported Dr. Dillahunt and research of the Social Innovations Group (SIG), which is focused on designing technologies to help low-resourced populations seek employment and education (Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt)

UX Team, Intel-NTU IoX Center

Taipei, Taiwan

Workshop Organizer

03/2015 - 05/2015

Organized the collaborative workshop on design thinking of Stanford d.school and National Taiwan University IoX Center

Research Assistant

07/2014 - 07/2015

Carried out research on user experience and natural user interface under smart environment as the only M.S. member in the team (Advisor: Dr. Bing-Yu Chen)

Collaborative & Social Computing Lab, Dept. CS, Natl. Tsing-Hua Univ.

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Collaborative Researcher

07/2014 - 07/2015

Led a project on friendsourcing, aiming to understand how social capital works when a SNS user requests resources on her/his own social network (Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang)

Taiwan Army (Mandatory Military Service)

Taichung, Taiwan

Company Chief Consultant (Second Lieutenant)

08/2013 - 07/2014

Handled psychological consulting, human resources management, and welfare of a military company with 40+ members

Intelligent Agents Lab, Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

System Administrator

03/2011 - 07/2013

Managed devices and web services for 30+ lab members

ROFESSIONAL SERVICES	
Academic Events & Activities	
ACM MobileHCI 2019	09/2017 - Present
Student Volunteer Chair	04 /0045 05 /0045
TaiCHI 2015 Organizing Committee	01/2015 - 07/2015
OpenHCI Workshop 2014 (student-organized workshop on HCI in Taiwan) Steering Committee	01/2014 - 07/2014
OpenHCI Workshop 2013 Program Chair	01/2013 - 07/2013
OpenHCI Workshop 2011 Registration and Volunteer Chair	01/2011 - 07/2011
Social Events & Activities	
Univ. of Michigan, School of Information	08/2018 - Present
Doctoral Committee - Student Representative	
Annual Taiwan Night at CHI Organizing Committee	2015 - 2018

Reviewer

ACM CHI 2017 - 2019; ACM CSCW 2017, 2018; ACM MobileHCI 2018; ACM TEI 2017

Conference Student Volunteer

ACM CSCW 2018; ACM COMPASS 2018; ACM CHI 2017

TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student Instructor	
School of Information, Univ. of Michigan	Winter 2018

SI-622: Usability Testing Instructor: Prof. Joyojeet Pal

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan Fall 2017

SI-501: Contextual Inquiry
Instructor: Prof. Kentaro Toyama
Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. &

Dept. Design, Natl. Taiwan Univ. of Tech. and Sci. Spring 2013

Advanced Human-Computer Interface/User-Oriented Innovation Design Instructor: Prof. Hsien-Hui Tang & Prof. Mike Y. Chen

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. Fall 2011

Introduction to Computer Science Instructor: Prof. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Student Team Coach

OpenHCI Workshop 2011 07/2011

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Autism Serves VolunteerTaipei, TaiwanStarRain Service Association for Autism02/2008 - 06/2013